Guide to the Phi Beta Kappa, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Phi Beta Kappa, Yale University, records
1786-1984
RU 58
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
11.5
The records consist of correspondence, manuscripts, scrapbooks, printed material, catalogues, dissertations, minutes, register books, membership lists, speeches, the original 1789 charter, and financial material documenting elections, presentations and addresses, honorary appointments and medalists, and other activities of the Connecticut Alpha chapter of Phi Beta Kappa at Yale.
Phi Beta Kappa. Connecticut Alpha (Yale University)
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies, and organizations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, manuscripts, scrapbooks, printed material, catalogues, dissertations, minutes, register books, membership lists, speeches, the original 1789 charter, and financial material documenting elections, presentations and addresses, honorary appointments and medalists, and other activities of the Connecticut Alpha chapter of Phi Beta Kappa at Yale.
College students -- Societies, etc.; Greek letter societies; Secret societies -- United States; Phi Beta Kappa. Connecticut Alpha (Yale University); Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students
- Records, 1786-1951; Accession 1952-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Letter from Joel Jones declining invitation to deliver Î¦BK oration, 1836 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Hon. Wm. Gaston declining invitation to deliver Î¦BK oration, 1836 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Application from Hampden Sydney College of Virginia. Signers: W.B. Dutton, John B. McThail, Wm. Maxwell, LL.D., CT Alpha; Hiram P. Goodrich, B.F. Stanton, James Wood, Philo Calhoun, NY Alpha; Samuel Hurd, New Hampshire Alpha (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letter from A.N. Minnen containing notice of letter 1 and 2, also notice of articles sent to the Trunk, 1837 March 18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Letter from Samuel Henry Dickson thanking for honorary appointment, 1836 August (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Brown Chapter giving date of formation of that chapter and list of member elected, 1830 September (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Edward A. Park declining invitation to deliver oration, 1840 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Jown Quincy declining invitation to deliver address, 1939 November (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Letter from Brown announcing formation of chapter, signed by J. Wayland, J. Wayland, Jr., and J.I. Waterman, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letter from Richard H. Dana declining invitation to deliver address, 1840 April (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letter from Willis Hall declining invitation to deliver address, 1836 August (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Acceptance of invitation to deliver poem by Grenville Mellen, 1839 May (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Declining invitation to speak, Thomas J. Oakley, 1935 October (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Declining presidency of CT Alpha, N.S. Williams, 1840 April (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Query regarding election of members, Rev. Caleb Stetson, 1837 July (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Declining to speak, Daniel Webster, 1833 September (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Acceptance to speak, Albert Barnes, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Recommendation from Harvard Chapter of election of Rev. John Pierpont to Yale Chapter, Charles Folsom, Secretary, 1828 September (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Acceptance from Fitz-Greene Halleck, 1828 October (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Declining to offer ØBK oration for publication, William M. Holland, 1829 October (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Declining to speak, William Ellsworth, 1829 April (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Acceptance to speak, Charles Atwood, 1827 June (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Acceptance to speak, E. Bailey, 1828 September (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Acceptance of election as honorary member, Eben Bailey, 1828 January (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Letter of thanks from William Holland, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Declining to speak, Jabez W. Huntington, 1827 July (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Acknowledgment of election, D.B. Douglass, 1829 September (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Declining to speak, William Johnson, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letter asking for reply to application by Jefferson College, Canonsburgh, signed by Alfred W. Marks, Lorman Crawford, 1829 April (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Declining to speak, William Johnson, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Request for Constitution from Thomas J. Waterman of Brown, 1830 July (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Acceptance, William Maxwell, 1827 November (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Declining to speak, William T. Dwight, 1827 December (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Declining to speak, Eben Bailey, 1829 August (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Declining to speak, Fitz-Greene Halleck, 1830 January (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Declining to speak, William Jay, 1828 September (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Acceptance to speak, Thomas S. Grimke, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Declining to speak, Samuel Hubbard, 1827 May (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Letter from Union College, information regarding date on key. G.B. Natt, 1827 June (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Acceptance to speak, Edward Everett, 11132 August (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Request for non-publication of letter, Edward Everett, 1832 August (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Request for speaking, Edward Everett, 1832 August (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Declining to speak, Horace Binney, 1835 August (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Acceptance to speak, William W. Andrews, 1835 July (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Declining to speak, William W. Andrews, 1835 July (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Declining to write poem, T.H. Gallaudet, 1834 June (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Query as to Kent's acceptance, Edward Everett [See letters from Edward Everett], 1830 September (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Acceptance to speak, Edward Everett, 1831 October (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Acceptance to speak, James Kent, 1830 September (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Conditional acceptance to speak, John Sargent, 1834 February (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Acknowledgment of invitation, Edward Everett, 1832 August (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Acceptance to speak, John Sargent, 1834 April (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Acknowledgment of election as honorary member, Samuel Foote, 1834 July (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Acknowledgment of election as honorary member, W. McKee Dunn, 1835 August (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Declining to speak, Moses Stuart, 1835 November (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Declining to speak, R.M. Sherman, 1834 January (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Declining to speak, R.M. Sherman, 1798 April (Box 1, Folder 56a)
  - Acceptance to speak, John Sargent, 1834 August (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Declining presidency, R.M. Sherman, 1832 December (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Letter from Dartmouth stating Webster a ØBK man, 1833 July (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Letter regarding initiation, R.M. Sherman, 1832 June (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Declining to speak, Theodore Dwight, 1832 December (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Letter of consent to meeting, R.M. Sherman, 1832 June (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Acceptance of presidency of CT Alpha, R.M. Sherman, 1829 December (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Declining to write poem, Eben Bailey, 1830 October (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Letter from Brown University asking for recognition of chapter, signed by J. Wayland, Jr., 1829 July (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Letter from Brown giving names of officers and members, 1831 September (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Acknowledgment of election as honorary member, C.N. Shepherd, 1829 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Acceptance to speak conditionally, R,M. Sherman, 1830 June (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Acceptance to speak, Alanson Hamlin, 1831 December (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Acknowledgment of election as honorary member, John Sargent, 1831 October (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - List of members of 1837 and 1838, Union College, Edward Savage, Sec., undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Acceptance to speak, Henry Barnard, 1845 June (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Declining to speak, Daniel Lord, 1840 June (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Query for information, Albert Barnes, 1840 July (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Information from Union College, members, officers, Edward Savage, 1839 July (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Declining to speak, John M. Clayton, 1847 August (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Acceptance to speak, S. North, 1846 Oct: (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Declining to speak, O.W. Holmes, 1847 September (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Declining to speak, Henry W. Longfellow, 1845 February (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Query for information from Bowdoin, 1846 October (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Declining to speak, Rufus Choate, 1844 December (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Conditional acceptance to speak, D.D. Barnard, 1845 October (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Query as to its charter, Dartmouth, E.R. Peaseley, Sec., 1845 November (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Declining to speak, Julius Rockwell, 1839 May (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Declining to speak, Horace Binney, 1845 March (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Conditional acceptance to speak, George Burgess, 1847 September (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Declining to speak, C.C. Fellin, 1857 May (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Acceptance to speak, F.M. Finch, 1857 May (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Query, Middletown charter from Brawn, George Chase, Sec., 1845 August (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Question of founding University of Vermont chapter from Dartmouth, 1845 April (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Query founding of chapter at Western Reserve University from Bowdoin, 1847 April (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - T. H. Gallaudet, 1816 October (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - W. Jay, 1816 October (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - T.H. Gallaudet, undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - L. Mitchell, 1822 June (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Judge Gould, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - L.P. Staples, 1823 August (Box 2, Folder 96a)
  - M. Hatch, 1814 June (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - J. Chester, 1815 October (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - T. Alden, 1811 October (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - J.C. Bates, 1809 July (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - N. Porter, 1815 June (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - I. Gould, 1808 October (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - I.M. Clay, 1808 June (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Rev. H. Humphrey, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - John Adams, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - S.E. Dwight, 1808 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - N. Darling, 1808 June (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - E. Waterman, 1808 November (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - R. Austin, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - E. Hubbard, 1803 January (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - A. Backus, 1802 November (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - W. Todd, 1816 July (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - W.F. Brainard, 1815 July (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Report of starting a ØBK pension fund, Benjamin Silliman, Chairman, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Vote to grant charter to Dartmouth, B. Bidwell, undated (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Report of amendments, signed by Henry T. Charming, Simeon Baldwin and Stephen W. Stebbins, 1782 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Vote to refuse chapter to Providence, 1790 or 1791 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Protest against resolution to abolish oath at initiation, 1809 September (Box 2, Folder 118)
    General
    Committee: Isaac M. Clay, Leonard E. Wales, Henry T. Strong Henry H. Bacot, John M. Austin, Eli Ives, M.D.; Signers: Samuel F. Jarvis, Nathan Johnson, William -----, Noyes Darling, Tutor, Hezekiah G. Ufford, Henry W. Channing, Jacob Sutherland, Curtiss Warner, John Dunwoody, Charles Chauncey, Jr., William M. Gibson, Justus McKinstrey, William M. Smith, Jonathan Knight, A.B. Northrop, Simeon Baldwin, James Gilbert, M.D., Robert Smith, Silas Robbins, Godrich Mallery.
  - Report on Pension Fund signed by Daniel Huntington, 1797 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Report on extending chapters to Princeton, Providence and Williams, 1798 December 5 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Laws of ØBK Society (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Amendment of the Constitution, William Botsford, 1792 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Report favoring a grant of Alpha Chapter to Union College, 1816 September (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Report of committee favoring a chapter at Union College, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Memorandum, 1815 October (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - First draft of a letter to the President at Cambridge, Barnabas Bidwell, Letter No. 5, undated (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Letter from Hezekiah Packard, Letter No. 7, 1788 September (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Letter from Samuel Kendall, Letter No. 2 (President), 1782 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Package of letters relating to Alpha of New Hampshire, undated (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Request for contribution to a literary work of ØBK from Sidney Willard, Sec., of Cambridge, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Communication from Harvard Chapter written by S.C. Thacher, 1809 December (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Catalogue of Harvard Chapter, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Communication from Cambridge by Sidney Willard, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Communication from Cambridge favoring chapter at Union, signed Andrew Norton, 1814 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Request from Harvard for chapter at Dartmouth, 1786 November (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Communication from Cambridge regarding establishment of chapter at Columbia, S.C., written by Samuel Gilrnan, 1818 July (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Communication from Harvard, by Joseph McKean, 1807 August (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Communication from Harvard, P. Nurse, 1808 May (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Report on Pension Fund from Harvard and list of members of 1797 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Communication from Harvard by Joseph McKean, 1806 September (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Communication from Harvard by Samuel Shapleigh, 1796 October (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Communication from Harvard by John Pipon, 1795 February (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Communication from Harvard by Thadeus M. Harris, 1790 August (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Communication from Harvard by A. Norton, 1814 August (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Communication from Harvard, celebration of anniversary, by Samuel Shapleigh, 1798 December (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Communication from Harvard in regard to charter of Union, 1817 April (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Communication from Harvard by William Harris, 1787 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Communication from Harvard, list of members of 1800, Sidney Willard, 1801 May (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Communication from Harvard, Thadeus M. Harris, 1792 March (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Communication from Harvard in regard to Brunswick application, Joseph Cogswell, 1823 July (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Communication from Harvard, lost papers, Henry Ware, 1787 March (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Communication from Harvard, Brown, Thomas Thompson, 1790 September (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Communication from Harvard founding of "Literary Miscellany," Sedney Willard, 1804 March (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Communication from Harvard, Peter Nurse, 1808 February (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Acceptance to deliver ØBK poem, W.C. Bryant, 1824 November (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Communication from Union College, Andrew Gates, Correspondence Secretary, 1824 August (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Acceptance to speak, James Gould, 1824 November (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Acceptance to speak, J.C. Bates, 1827 January (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Catalogue of members of Yale College, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Acceptance to speak, James G. Brooks, 1826 June (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Declining to speak, Charles Atwood, 1825 August (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - List of officers and members of Union College, Alonzo Potter, 1825 September (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Communication of correction, Henry Channing, 1826 October (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Declining to speak, James R. Gould, 1825 August (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Acceptance, John Trumbull, 1824 November (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Resolution passed by Society in regard to 164 [Declining to speak, James R. Gould], undated (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Notice of refusal, A.C. Twining, 1827 April (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Petition for chapter from Bowdoin, Parker Cleaveland, 1824 September (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Declining to speak, William Maxwell, 1827 January (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Declining to speak, J.C. Calhoun, 1827 February (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Treasurer's book and papers (not in collection), J.G.E. Larned, Treasurer, Yale College, 1847-1950 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - Request for charter from Union College, 1813 July (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - Catalogue of members, Union College, 1817 and 1818 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Account of commencement, Union College, Andrew Gates, 1822 October (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Organization of society at Union College, McAuley, 1818 July (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Acceptance, Julius Rockwell, 1838 November (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Petition for charter from University of City of New York, 1836 December (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Acceptance, H. Humphrey, 1838 February (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - Resolution regarding granting of charter adopted, 1839 August (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - Treasurer's report, Joseph G.E. Lamed; receipts, 1844-47 (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - Communication from Harvard, undated (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - Advice from Henry T. Channing, 1782 December (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - Communication from Edward Bristol, 1826 June (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - Communication from David Daggett, 1827 Aug (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - Declining to speak, William C. Bryant, 1825 June (Box 3, Folder 185)
  - Demand for money, Theophilus Smith, 1825 July (Box 3, Folder 186)
  - Refusal to pay fine, Samuel Phelps, 1811 August (Box 3, Folder 187)
  - Acknowledgment of receipts of catalogue, T.J. Oakley, 1813 July (Box 3, Folder 188)
  - Account of election, Sedgwick, 1823 February (Box 3, Folder 189)
  - Demand for money, Theophilus Smith, 1824 June (Box 3, Folder 190)
  - Acknowledgment of receipt, G. Granger, 1813 July (Box 3, Folder 191)
  - Recommendation of Eston, 1794 July (Box 3, Folder 192)
  - Acknowledgment of admission, J.P. Williams, 1823 February (Box 3, Folder 193)
  - Communication of Baldwin and brothers of Î¦BK at Albany, 1783 (Box 3, Folder 194)
  - Refusal to grant charter to Hampden Sydney College in Virginia, D. Olmstead, Chairman, 1828 August (Box 3, Folder 195)
  - Report of Treasurer, E.C. Herrick, 1838 December (Box 3, Folder 196)
  - Acknowledgment of catalogue, J. Lovett, 1813 July (Box 3, Folder 197)
  - Communication from Harvard, 1782 (Box 3, Folder 198)
  - Catalogue of Harvard ØBK
    - 1790-1791 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - 1798 (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - 1793-1796 (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - 1798-1800 (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - 1772-1809 (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - 1801 (Box 3, Folder 204)
    - 1794 (Box 3, Folder 205)
    - 1786-1787 (Box 3, Folder 206)
    - 1790, 1793, 1797 (Box 3, Folder 207)
    - 1781-1786 (Box 3, Folder 208)
    - 1789, 1792, 1803 (Box 3, Folder 209)
  - Records of ØBK, 1787 (Box 3, Folder 210)
  - Oration on Languages, E.G. Marsh, 1797 (Box 3, Folder 211)
  - Oration Fourth of July, M. Bidwell, 1795 (Box 3, Folder 212)
  - Oration, Timothy Bigelow, 1791 (Box 3, Folder 213)
  - Fragment of Oration, undated (Box 3, Folder 214)
  - Catalogue of Yale ØBK (not in collection), 1821-1838 (Box 3, Folder 215 - 220)
  - Dissertation by David Chapin, 1798 (Box 3, Folder 221)
  - Dissertation by Calvin Chapin, 1788 (Box 3, Folder 221a)
  - Oration by T. William Johnson, 1793 (Box 3, Folder 222)
  - Oration delivered by J. Walter Edwards, 1791 (Box 4, Folder 223)
  - Resolution passed concerning Wesleyan, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - Resolution passed concerning stealing of the trunk, 1786 December (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Query from Harvard, undated (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - Cipher letter from Harvard (not in collection), 1782 March (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - Copy of form of initiation (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Oration, 1798 (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - Letter from John Beckley, 1782 July (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Report of Committee on restoring certain parts of secrecy, D. Olmstead, Chairman, undated (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - Forms of oath for Richard McCurdy and Hugo Burgharst, undated (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Ceremonies adopted, 1779 (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Letter from Williamsburgh, Fragment, 1782 (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - Receipt signed by 1887 (not in collection) (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - Catalogue of members, Yale (not in collection), 1853-98 (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Oration by Albert Barnes (not in collection), 1840 (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - History of the Society, undated (Box 4, Folder 238)
  - Forms of Charter Party, 1779 (Box 4, Folder 239)
  - Constitution, 1787 (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - Constitution, 1807 (Box 4, Folder 241)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1826 July - 1846 December (Box 4, Folder 242)
  - July, 1801 - June 1813 (Box 4, Folder 243)
  - August, 1787 - June 1801 (Box 4, Folder 244)
  - 1813 - 1826 (Box 5, Folder 245)
  - Minutes, 1867, 1869, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 246)
  - Correspondence between Alphas, 1802 (Box 5, Folder 247)
  - Oration, Timothy Pitkin, 1792 (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - Form of a charter-party (facsimile), 1779 (Box 5, Folder 249)
  - Correspondence from ØBK members, 1861-1909 (Box 5, Folder 250)
  - Letter from William Irvine, 1796 (Box 5, Folder 251)
  - Letter from Timothy Dwight, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 251a)
  - Poem by James G. Brooks, 1826 (Box 5, Folder 252)
  - Poem by Grenville Mellen, 1839 (Box 5, Folder 253)
  - Poem by Daniel March, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 254)
  - Poem by Oliver Wendell Holmes, 1850 (Box 5, Folder 255)
  - Poem by Champion Bissell, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 256)
  - Oration by Charles Chauncey, 1797 (Box 5, Folder 257)
  - Oration by Edward Everett, 1824 (Box 5, Folder 258)
  - Oration by James A. Hillhouse, 1826 (Box 5, Folder 259)
  - Oration by Denison Olmstead, 1827 (Box 5, Folder 260)
  - Oration by Edward Everetts, 1833 (Box 5, Folder 261)
  - Oration by S. Henry Dickson, 1842 (Box 5, Folder 261a)
  - Oration by William Sprague, 1845 (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - Oration by Horace Bushnell, 1848 (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Oration by Elisha Cleaveland, 1853 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Oration by Andrew D. White, 1866 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Oration by Emory Washburne, 1870 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Oration by Arthur T. Vanderbilt, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Fragment of an oration, undated (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - ØBK catalogue, 1808 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - ØBK catalogue, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Correspondence among various Alphas, 1782-1799 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Correspondence among various Alphas (bound), 1782-1799 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1904-1941 (Box 7, Folder 273 - 275)
  - Scrapbook, 1912-1931 (Box 7, Folder 276)
  - Roll Call Book, 1895-1933 (Box 7, Folder 277)
  - Constitutions and Signatures, 1905-1931 (Box 7, Folder 278)
  - Statistical Blanks for 1905 Catalogue, A - Z (Box 8, Folder 279 - 281)
  - Unidentified Notes of ØBK speech, 1916 February 25 (Box 8, Folder 282)
  - Miscellaneous ØBK material, envelopes from Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 283)
  - Post card votes on granting of new charter, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 284)
  - Print of the Rev. Timothy Dwight, undated (Box 9, Folder 285)
  - Excerpts on ØBK from William Lathrop Kingsley's Yale College: A- Sketch of its History, vol 1 pp. 324-8, 1787, 1792 (Box 9, Folder 286)
  - Biographies of ØBK men, 1829-1838 (Box 9, Folder 287)
  - Excerpts of numbered correspondence, 1787-1846 (Box 9, Folder 288)
  - Copies of Numbered Correspondence and documents, 1777-1935 (Box 9, Folder 289 - 292)
  - ØBK Correspondence, 1933-1937 (Box 9, Folder 293)
  - Autograph lists of class members, A-T, 1931-1950 (Box 10, Folder 294)
  - Acceptances of graduate membership, signed, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 295)
  - ALS Samuel Kendak, charter, Alpha Chapter William and Mary College (copy), 1782 (Box 10, Folder 296)
  - Alpha of Connecticut: blank invitaitons to initiation, undated (Box 10, Folder 297)
  - Committee on Policy to the Senate, From the report of the, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 298)
  - Constitution of the Yale Chapter on ØBK, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 299)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 10, Folder 300)